shubhyatra.com 2001-02-03

# Shubhyatra : Privacy Policies

|  | 

> **_Privacy Policy_**
> 
> You are in control of the information you provide to Shubhyatra.com.
> 
> As a member of Shubhyatra.com, you are in complete control of your travel planning needs. This includes controlling the use of information you provide to Shubhyatra.com. The bottom line is that we respect and will continue to respect the privacy of our customers who use Shubhyatra.com and our reservations system.
> 
> Because protecting your privacy is important to us, you can be assured that Shubhyatra.com discloses the following:
> 
>   * What personal information is being gathered about you and how the information will be used
>   * Who the information will be shared with (if anyone) 
>   * An opt out policy 
>   * Access to your information (including how to update or correct inaccuracies) 
>   * Safeguards in place to protect your information 
>   * Other information about your privacy
> 

> 
> **What personal information Shubhyatra.com is gathering and how is this information being used?**
> 
> _Member Registration  
>  _ When you become a Shubhyatra.com member you provide your name, address, telephone number, email address, a unique login name, password, and password validation. This information is collected on the registration form for several reasons including: (i) personal identification; (ii) to complete air, car, and hotel reservations; (iii) to allow us to contact you for customer service, if necessary; (iv) to customize the content of our site to meet your specific needs; and (v) to make product improvements to Shubhyatra.com. In addition, your email address is collected to send you an email message confirming your new member registration and each reservation you transact online. As a member you will occasionally receive updates from us about fare sales in your area, special offers, new Shubhyatra.com services, and other noteworthy news items. However, you may always decline to receive these email messages. Please see our Opt Out policy described below.
> 
> _Member Profile  
>  _ Members can choose to provide Shubhyatra.com with travel preferences, credit card billing information, ticket delivery address, travel agency preference and other personal information. This information is primarily used to assist members in making reservations quickly without having to type in the same information repeatedly. For example, members can store their airline frequent flyer numbers so that when a reservation is made on that airline, Shubhyatra.com automatically pre-fills the frequent flyer number input box.
> 
> _Newsletters and Fare Watcher  
>  _ Shubhyatra.com's newsletters (if applicable) and Fare Watcher (to be introduced shortly) are optional benefits for members that keep you up to date with the latest travel news and low airfares. Fare Watcher tracks the prices of airline tickets to your favourite places. When the price for one of your favourite trips changes based on your preferences, Shubhyatra.com will notify you of the change via email. Your email address and preferred round trip city pairs are necessary to receive Fare Watcher emails. 
> 
> _Contests  
>  _ Shubhyatra.com sometimes sponsors contests to give members the opportunity to win great travel prizes. Information collected by Shubhyatra.com for such contests can include contact information and survey questions. Contact information is used to notify contest winners and survey information is used to develop promotions and product improvements to Shubhyatra. 
> 
> _Online Surveys  
>  _ Shubhyatra.com values opinions and comments from members, so we frequently conduct online surveys.These surveys are entirely optional for all members. Typically, the information is aggregated and used to make improvements to Shubhyatra.com and to develop appealing content, features and promotions for members. Survey participants are anonymous unless otherwise stated in the survey. 
> 
> _Cookies  
>  _ "Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Shubhyatra.com uses cookies in several ways. We use cookies to allow you to login without having to type your login name each time. Instead, only your password is needed to access the system. We also use cookies to track usage of the "Guest" path and to serve advertisements through our advertising networks. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. 
> 
> _IP Addresses  
>  _ Shubhyatra.com collects IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our servers and for system administration. 
> 
> Please be aware that we have links on our site that may collect personally identifiable information about you. This Privacy Statement does not cover the information practices or policies of such Web sites. 
> 
> **Who will the information be shared with, if anyone?**  
>  When you reserve or purchase travel services through Shubhyatra.com, we provide information about you to the airline, car rental agency, hotel, travel agency or other involved third party to ensure the successful fulfilment of your travel arrangements. 
> 
> We do not sell individual customer names or other private profile information to third parties and have no intention of doing so in the future. Occasionally, Shubhyatra.com will hire a third party to act on our behalf for projects such as market research surveys and contest entry processing and will provide information to these third parties specifically for use in connection with these projects. The information we provide to such third parties is protected by a confidentiality agreement and is to be used solely for completing the specific project. See below. 
> 
> _**Opt Out Policy**  
>  _ At anytime, you can unsubscribe to ShubhYatra's newsletters or the Fare Watcher (when introduced). **To unsubscribe,** send e-mail to [shubhnews-request@shubhyatra.com](mailto:shubhnews-request@shubhyatra.com): with **“Unsubscribe <e-mail address>” **(without the quotes and < >) as the ** >first line of your message ** As a member or contest entrant you will occasionally receive email updates from us about fare sales in your area, special offers, new Shubhyatra.com services and other noteworthy news items. We hope you will find these updates interesting and informative. Shubhyatra.com reserves the right to limit membership to those who will accept emails. Members will be notified via email prior to any actions taken. 
> 
> **How can you access, update or correct your information?**  
>  At any time, you can view and/or update your Contact Info, alternative email ID and Shubhyatra.com's newsletter subscriptions or your personal profile, which includes member registration and travel preferences information, by following the Account Info link on your My Sawaal page. 
> 
> **What safeguards are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of your information?**  
>  All information you provide to Shubhyatra.com is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. In addition, when you make travel purchases on Shubhyatra.com, you are protected by Shubhyatra.com's Shop Safe Guarantee.
> 
> **What other information should I know about my privacy?  
>  ** Shubhyatra.com contains links to other Web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another Web site for which Shubhyatra.com has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of all such sites as their policies may be materially different from Shubhyatra.com's Privacy Statement. Of course, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and any account information. Please be very careful, responsible, and alert with this information, especially whenever you're online.
> 
> In addition to the circumstances described above, Shubhyatra.com may disclose member information if required to do so by law, court order, as requested by other government or law enforcement authority, or in the good faith belief that disclosure is otherwise necessary or advisable including, without limitation, to protect the rights or properties of Shubhyatra.com or Sabre, Inc. or when we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing interference with our rights or properties, whether intentionally or otherwise, or when anyone else could be harmed by such activities.
> 
> Any material changes in the way Shubhyatra.com uses personal information will be described in future versions of this Privacy Statement. Of course, you may always submit concerns regarding our Privacy Statement or our privacy practices to [feedback@shubhyatra.com](http://www.shubhyatra.com/htm/feedback.htm). Please reference the privacy policy in your subject line. Shubhyatra.com will attempt to respond to all reasonable concerns or inquiries within five business days of receipt.
> 
> **TOP**

**_

* * *

_ **

Copyright © 2000 [ Shubhyatra.com](http://www.shubhyatra.com/index.htm) India Pvt. Ltd. All rights reserved.
